# Michael Nguyen

me @ michael-nguyen.dev | 408-334-2572

# **ABOUT ME**

I am a front-end developer who focuses on SEO, speed, and user experience.

# **TECHNOLOGY**

[Front] React, NextJS, Astro, Tailwind [Back] AWS, Flask, Firebase, NodeJS [Code] CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Python [Tools] Photoshop, Postman, Premiere Pro, VScode

# EDUCATION

#### **B.Sc. in Computer Science**

University of California, Santa Cruz 2016 - 2018

# LINKS

**5** github

in linkedin

website

#### CERTIFICATES

2022 - Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate.

2021 - Google IT Automation with Python by Google.

#### HOBBIES & INTERESTS

I love learning new technologies, traveling, playing the piano, and hanging out with my cats.

# **EXPERIENCE**

Clear Bounce - Front End Developer | Owner

Feb 2019 - Present

• A digital agency that specializes in helping local business owners build an online presence through search engine optimization, social media, and content creation.

Apple - Quality Assurance Technician

Oct 2021 - March 2022

- Supported iPhone and Air Pods hardware engineering teams by identifying component issues during product launches.
- Performed extensive tests to gauge proper functionality while documenting specific configurations for proper test cycles.
- Utilized Radar, Apple's internal bug reporting software, to update and escalate hardware issues to engineering teams.

View, Inc - Software Engineer

Dec 2018 - July 2019

- Developed and maintained product user interfaces in a iterative SCRUM-based approach.
- Ensured mobile friendliness and responsiveness on the minimal viable product.
- Collaborated with design teams to align with new changes and expectations.

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

Local SEO Kit Jul - Aug 2022

• Full stack app that contains AI and SEO tools.

· React, Firebase, AWS, Beanstalk, Flask, Python, JavaScript

Stock Nitro Sep 2022

· A paper trading simulator and trading journal.

· NextJS, Firebase, Vercel, JavaScript

Action Hustle Sep 2022

• Entrepreneurship blog and e-learning website.

· Astro, Firebase, Vercel, JavaScript

# **CLIENT WORK**

**South Bay Hers** - Air Duct Cleaning

• Full digital suite including website, social media, logo & branding, and SEO.

We Buy Houses In Bay Area - Real Estate

• Ranked top ten for 50+ keywords related to real estate.

Authentic Auto Sales - Used Car Dealership

· Auto updates for new inventory.

Last updated September 27, 2022

2022

2019

2019